# Mark Gandolfo

0407 021014 - mark@gandolfo.com.au - markgandolfo.com

## **Senior Product Manager**

Digital Product Manager with extensive experience in the delivery of successful products to market. I am driven by the idea that there is a better way to identify business opportunities, to launch new products to market, to run technology-focused teams, and to build innovative software.

### **Professional History**

#### **Hooroo - Qantas Hotels**

May 2015 - Current

Product Manager

Hired as the third Product Manager when Hooroo was a small company of 20 (now 150), I was brought on board to deliver growth. I later moved into core platform enablement (consumer payments, fraud, finance reporting, supplier payments) before finally moving into partner services to support our suppliers.

- Created a B2B feedback program Coined Qantas Hotels Partner Loop to engage our 1500 hotel partners in the build of our platform
- Analytics and business intelligence dashboards creation to measure new ideas, track the success of deployed features, and radiate information throughout the organisation.
- **Identifying the highest value opportunities** to be delivered by the team using collaborative workshops, customer interviews, and stakeholder engagement.
- Joint collaboration of payment strategy with Qantas Payment Team to bring a single gateway across the group (47 merchants), a credit card vault to store network tokens, a fraud strategy (behavioural & rule based), and a scheme based gift card solution.
- Redesign of the search results page resulting in 7% uptick in bookings and 2% increase in time on page
- Identified key serviceability gap during customer research replayed research to leadership team and pitched investment in improvements to the post booking experience which resulted in usage by +3000 users per day, avg happiness 4.5 / 5, and \$150k in repeat bookings per week.
- **Identified luxury hotels** as being under-represented resulting in the launch of 'Exclusive Qantas Hotels' resulting in \$1.6M per month in revenue
- **Created strategy template** which was adopted throughout the organisation to align the squads and product teams.
- Stakeholder and vendor management across the Qantas machine including executive team, marketing, sales, vendors, in various locations around the globe.

Mark Gandolfo 0407 02 1014

**APN Digital** 2010 – 2015

Product Manager (3 years), Development & Delivery Manager (2 years)

Responsible for a team of 15 including Product, Development, UX, and Support. We managed readership growth and commercialisation of 47 digital news mastheads. Focus was on the development of core editorial and commercial products within a single bespoke CMS, in order to support the transition of readership from print to web.

- Mentored and elevated my team in product and UX practices such as Lean,
  Design Thinking, Design Sprints, Interviews and Synthesis to build better products
- **Re-launched online retail classifieds** connecting private and commercial sellers to buyers across multiple verticals (cars, jobs, general classifieds, properties).
- Re-launched Regional News Network user research driven re-launch of 47 news mastheads, leading to 35% increase in daily visitors
- Launched an experimental social community an enhanced online news site without the legacy of the core mastheads, allowing for faster testing of hypothesis which if proven right are rolled back into the legacy brands.
- Introduced digital subscriptions and a paywall analysed data, built a commercial model and delivered a solution that saw 5% of users purchase monthly subscriptions resulting in \$1.2M / month revenue
- Increased high-value saleable advertising inventory by introducing a data management platform (Lotame) to segment customers, publish inventory via DSP/SSP, enabling off-network partnerships

Mocra 2009 – 2010

Senior Software Consultant

Mocra was a 10 person consultancy specialising in the development of web based applications. My responsibility was for relationship and delivery of client needs, including problem identification, solution design, delivery and iteration.

#### **Avalon Property Group**

2008 - 2009

Software Developer

APG is a franchised home builder operating within Australia I was responsible for the creation of an online sales portal for customers to customise their future home. This integrated with a large Windows based application that provided options and costs.

**APN Online** 2007 – 2008

Technical Business Analyst

My role was to integrate legacy publishing and classified products to the new online database.

Mark Gandolfo 0407 02 1014

#### **Side-hustles & Associations**

**Product Tank Melbourne** 

since 2015

**Ruby Australia** 

since 2013

**Aus Innovation Community Leaders** 

since 2019

**Startup Vic** 

since 2019

AussieV8.com.au

1999 - current

A community for car enthusiasts, 35k registered users, 60k MUU. Advertising supported.

**Grain & Malt** 2003 - 2005

A whisky tasting subscription, delivered in the mail.

Lytebulb

in development

Our mission is to reduce the disparity in education in Australia.

**Software / PM Mentor** 

unpaid - ongoing

**Product Management &** Junior Software Engineering mentor. 7 mentees to date.

**Advisory Role** ongoing

Mental health startup, helping to maximise efficiency of doctors treating adolescents

**Advisory Role (Heystack)** 

ongoing

Mission is to drive increase in application to interview rate for job seekers using smart media

Mark Gandolfo 0407 02 1014

# **Education**

2019	Conflict without casualties - 2 day workshop Nate Regier
2017	Insights for Innovation Ideo University
2016	Storytelling for business Udemy
2015	Introduction to Game Development Michigan State University (coursera)
2015	Software Product Management University of Alberta (coursera)
2014	Programming Mobile Applications University of Maryland (coursera)
2007	Scrum Master Accreditation - 5 day workshop Gabrielle Benefield - Scrum Alliance
2003-2006	Bachelor of Computer Science Latrobe University
2001	Diploma of Computer Systems & CCNA NMIT

Mark Gandolfo 0407 02 1014